# 哎 小卤肉
Yo, braised pork!
# 我一听说小魏要吃这饭
As soon as I heard that Chef Xiao Wei is making this dish…
# 大爷 我中午没吃饭
Da Ye, I didn’t have lunch today.
# 我也没吃啊
I didn’t have any either.
# 嗯
Yum.
# 好
Good.
# 老饭骨版的霸王卤肉饭
Lao Fan Gu’s version of Super Star Braised Pork over Rice.
# 干葱 蒜片
Shallot slices, garlic slices,…
# 还有洋葱我们把它炸成金黄色
…and Onion. We are frying them till golden.
# 留一部分
Save some.
# 这时候把大葱搁进去
Now we add in some spring onion.
# 要分头炸
You have to fry them separately.
# 不然的话炸的大葱都干了
Otherwise the spring onion would be too dehydrated…
# 洋葱还不行呢
…while the onion is not ready at all.
# 大火 浸炸
High heat. The items should be bathing in the oil.
# 这时候就行了 关火
Ok, this works. Turn off the heat.
# 给它捞出来 备用
Scoop it up and put it on the side.
# 葱油有点多
We have a bit of extra scallion oil.
# 要留点出来
Let’s put some away.
# 五花肉切成条
Cut the pork belly into slim pieces with the layers on the long side.
# 以往的台湾卤肉饭就是小条
Taiwan style Braised Pork over Rice typically applies such size.
# 我今天配两块大个的
Today I am making two big ones.
# 霸王桩
Super Stars.
# 切下刀它就能够一块熟了
I am adding some carves so that they can be cooked alongside the small ones at the same time.
# 这吃的就过瘾
This must be very fulfilling to eat.
# 开始可以煸了
Now we can start to fry them in shallow oil.
# 大料瓣 炸香
Star anise. Fry till the smell comes out.
# 这时候咱就把这个
At this moment, we add …
# （霸王桩）生煸
…the Super Stars into the pot.
# 把肉给它推进去
Push in the meat.
# 连葱一块下去
Together with the spring onion and the shallot slices.
# 主要突出干葱跟大葱的香气
This gives a highlight of the smell of the shallot and spring onion.
# 咱这肉煸到什么程度
When should the meat be ready?
# 洋葱跟大葱还有干葱
When the onion, sprint onion, and shallot..
# （煸成）金黄色
…become golden.
# 香菇必须给它攥干水分
We need to squish the water out of the shiitake mushroom before it hits the pot.
# 生抽 顺着锅边
Add some light soy sauce from the inner side of the pot.
# 烹出香气来
The steam smells great.
# 沙嗲酱
Some satay sauce.
# 炒一炒
Fry them.
# 加水
Add some water.
# 老抽
Dark soy sauce.
# 再来点水
Add more water.
# 胡椒粉来点
Some white pepper powder.
# 少来点儿玫瑰露酒
A little bit rose wine.
# 增香 有玫瑰香味的酒
This wine with rosy smell adds even more flavor to the dish.
# 炸好的干葱洋葱搁进去
Now add in the previously fried shallot and onion.
# 搁到砂煲里头
Pour everything into the casserole.
# 炖制
Stew them.
# 开锅该调颜色了
Upon boiling, we adjust the toning (with dark soy sauce here).
# 盖上盖 得了
Cover it up. Solid.
# 炖了20来分钟了
Now we have stewed them for more than 20 minutes.
# 把这个鸡蛋给它搁进去
We add some boiled eggs.
# 泡上 小卤肉
Soak them well. Braised pork.
# 好 炖着吧
Ok, let the casserole stew.
# 炖了半小时又闷了10分钟
Now it’s another half an hour and 10 minutes.
# 可以啊
Looks great.
# 肉出锅了 卤肉
It’s show time for the Braised Pork!
# 霸王在这呢
Our Super Start is here!
# 老饭骨版的霸王卤肉饭
Lao Fan Gu’s version of Super Start Braised Pork over Rice.
# 齐活
Ready to serve.
# 好
Tasty.
# 嚯 也扒拉着吃
Look at you, you can’t wait to having a mouthful of food.
# 香吗
Doesn’t it taste good?
# 真香
Very good.
# 不能影响二伯形象
Er Bai still needs his image.
# 好吃啊 大爷
Delicious, Da Ye.
# 一般在做菜当中
Usually when we cook,…
# 用玫瑰酒特别少
… it’s very rare to use rose wine.
# 做的非常精致
The fact that Chef Xiao Wei used it here makes the dish exquisite.
# 我融入了咱
I integrated our…
# 山东菜的葱烧海参的手法
… Shandong Cuisine’s cooking method for Sea Cucumber Fried with Spring Onion.
# 原来没有大料瓣
We don’t typically use star anise in braised pork.
# 没加大葱
No spring onion either.
# 我在原有的基础上
On top of the tradition,…
# 加了葱烧海参的技法
… I integrated the cooking method for Sea Cucumber Fried with Spring Onion.